She walked off the street, into his life and stole his heart.
Pretty Woman is a romance, comedy film directed by Garry Marshall.
While on a business trip in Los Angeles, Edward Lewis, a millionaire entrepreneur who makes a living buying and breaking up companies, picks up a prostitute, Vivian, while asking for directions; after, Edward hires Vivian to stay
with him for the weekend to accompany him to a few social events, and the two get closer only to discover there are significant hurdles to overcome as they try to bridge the gap between their very different worlds.
Edward Lewis, played by Richard Gere.
Vivian Ward, played by Julia Roberts.
James Morse, played by Ralph Bellamy.
Philip Stuckey, played by Jason Alexander.
Kit De Luca, played by Laura San Giacomo.
The Hotel Manager, played by Héctor Elizondo.
Pretty Woman is a 1990 American romantic comedy-drama film
directed by Garry Marshall and written by J.
The film stars Richard Gere and Julia Roberts, and features Héctor Elizondo, Ralph Bellamy (in his
final performance), Laura San Giacomo, and Jason Alexander in supporting roles.
The film's story centers on Hollywood escort Vivian Ward
and wealthy corporate raider Edward Lewis.
Vivian is hired to be Edward's escort for several business and social functions,
and their relationship develops during her week-long stay with him.
The film's title Pretty Woman is based on the 1964
song "Oh, Pretty Woman" by Roy Orbison.
The original screenplay was titled 3000 and was
written by then-struggling screenwriter J.
Originally intended to be a dark cautionary tale about class and prostitution in Los
Angeles, the film was reconceived as a romantic comedy with a large budget.
Pretty Woman received mixed reviews from critics upon release, but widespread praise
was directed towards Roberts' performance and her chemistry with Gere.
It had the highest number of ticket sales in the US ever for a romantic comedy, with Box Office Mojo listing it as the number-one romantic comedy by
the highest estimated domestic tickets sold at 42,176,400, slightly ahead of My Big Fat Greek Wedding (2002) at 41,419,500 tickets.
The film grossed US$463.4 million worldwide and at the time of its release, was the
fifth-highest-grossing film of all time worldwide, behind only E.T.
the Extra-Terrestrial ($701 million at the time), Star Wars ($530 million at the time), Indiana Jones
and the Last Crusade ($474 million at the time), and Jaws ($470 million at the time).
It was also the highest-grossing R-rated film of all time (surpassing Rain Man) until it was surpassed by Terminator 2: Judgment Day in 1991, but remained the highest-grossing
R-rated film released by Walt Disney Studios, (surpassing Cocktail), holding the record for 34 years until Marvel Studios' Deadpool & Wolverine surpassed it in 2024.
Pretty Woman catapulted Roberts to superstardom, earning her the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress – Motion Picture Comedy or Musical, in
addition to her first nominations for the Academy Award for Best Actress and the BAFTA Award for Best Actress in a Leading Role.
The film also received nominations for the BAFTA Award for Best Film and the
Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of prostitute, sports car,
capitalism, expensive restaurant, workaholic.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.